drmartens.com 2011-05-16

# Privacy Policy and Terms of Use

This Site and its information suppliers make no representations or warranties of any kind with respect to services, information or data made available by This Site, including but not limited to the warranties of fitness for a particular purpose or merchantability or non-infringement.  This Site and its information suppliers make no representations or warranties of any kind with respect to the truth, accuracy or completeness of any statements, information, materials, services or data made available by This Site in the Internet site.

This Site and its information suppliers assume no responsibility in connection with the use made available by This Site  In no event shall This Site or its information suppliers be liable for any delays or failures in performance or for any interruption of this Internet site. In no event shall This Site or its information suppliers be liable for any special, incidental, indirect, punitive, or consequential damages or for the loss of profit, revenue, or data however they may arise, even if the user or viewer of this Internet site has been advised of the possibility of potential loss or damage.  This Site does not warrant or make representations or endorsements as to the quality, content, accuracy, or completeness of the information, text, graphics, links, and other items contained on this server or any other server.  Such materials have been compiled from a variety of sources, and are subject to change without notice from This Site as a result of updates and corrections.

Unless otherwise legally permissible, commercial use of the materials is prohibited without the written permission of This Site  All trademarks mentioned herein are the property of their respective owners.  Some of the links on this and subsequent pages may lead to resources outside This Site's control.  The user of these resources or links should not construe the presence of these links as an endorsement.  This Site is not responsible for the content of such external link.  Communications made through E-mail and Messaging system shall in no way be deemed to constitute legal notice to This Site or any of its agencies, officers, employees, agents, or representatives.

**Dr. Martens Privacy Policy**

Effective Date: December 1, 2009

_This Site (as defined below) is operated in the State of Oregon in the United States of America. Consequently, by entering it, you understand and agree that your actions on this Site are governed by the laws of the State of Oregon and the United States of America as applicable (the "Governing Laws"). Please be aware that your rights under the Governing Laws may be different than those of where you reside. Specifically, the regulatory, reporting and disclosure obligations of the site operators may require the sharing of your personal information with foreign third parties and law enforcement agencies to fulfill their legal obligations._

We value your privacy. This notice describes the Privacy Policy (“Policy”) and practices of our site, www.drmartens.com (the “Site”). We have implemented this Policy to describe the types of information that we collect, what we do with it, how we protect it and when we disclose it to third parties. Please read the following Policy to understand how your personal information will be treated as you use the Site. By visiting our Site, you are accepting the practices described in this Policy. This Policy is subject to change from time to time. You should periodically check the Site for updates.

Our Site may reference or contain links to other websites operated and maintained by third parties. Other websites may reference or link to our Site. These sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of other websites. You should review the privacy policies of each site you visit before disclosing any personal information.

**Information We Collect**

  * _Personal Information You Provide_. We collect information that you provide to us through our Site that is used to identify you personally (“personal information”) when we provide customer service or you place an order, register with us, send us an email, sign up for our newsletter, call us, complete a survey or enter a sweepstakes or contest. Personal information includes your name, mailing address, billing address, email address, telephone number and credit card information. This information may also include any preference information you provide to us, including a record of your online product purchases or information you submit about other people, for example the name and address of a gift recipient.
  *  _Other Information that is Automatically Collected_. Our web servers automatically collect certain types of information about your computer hardware and software when you visit our Site. This information may include your domain name, IP address(es), type of browser you use, dates and times of your visits, page visits, the website from which your visit originated, time spent on web pages and other similar traffic data. No personal information is automatically collected. This information may be used by us to operate the Site and to provide general statistics regarding the use of the Site.
  *  _Cookies._ Cookies are bits of information that are sent to your browser and stored on your computer’s hard drive. We use cookies to customize your visits to our Site by customizing your shopping experience and keeping track of your shopping cart. Cookies allow us to more easily communicate and interact with you. You may disallow cookies through your browser and still browse and shop our Site. However, if you set your browser so that it does not accept cookies, you may not be able to access certain features of our Site.
  *  _Information from Other Sources_. We may obtain information about you from outside sources and combine it with your account information. For example, we may use commercially available demographics and other marketing information from third parties to help us better serve you or inform you about products or services that we think will be of interest to you. We sometimes receive updated delivery and address information from our shippers or other sources so that we can correct our records and deliver your next purchase or communication more easily. Finally, we may also purchase lists containing your personal information (i.e. postal address, phone number, email address) for advertising and marketing purposes.

**  
Use of Information**

Except as follows, we will not disclose your personal information to third parties who are not our affiliates without your consent.

  * _Disclosure to Successors_. We may disclose your personal information to any actual or potential successor-in-interest of ours, such as a company that is seeking to acquire us, the Site, or the business and activities carried on via the Site. ****
  *  _Third-Party Service Providers and Suppliers_. We may disclose your personal information to third-party service providers who help us provide or maintain the Site. These companies may collect information about your domain type, IP address, and click stream information. Where you have purchased goods or services from the Site, we will need to give your information to third party suppliers in order to complete your transaction. We require that these third-party service providers and suppliers implement and maintain reasonable practices to protect your personal information and do not use it for any purpose other than in connection with the Site. ****
  *  _Other Disclosure_. We will disclose your personal information without your consent to prevent an emergency, to protect or enforce our rights, to protect or enforce the rights of a third party, or as required or permitted by law (including, without limitation, to comply with a subpoena or court order).

**  
Your California Privacy Rights**

Under California law, you have the right to request and receive information from retailers concerning any third parties who have received personal information about you from the retailers for the third parties' direct marketing purposes. Any such requests for information from us can be made by sending an e-mail through the Contact Us page on the Site located at http://www.drmartens.com/Contact.asp or by calling us at 1-800-810-6673.

**  
Correcting or Updating Information**

We endeavor to keep our customer records complete and accurate. If your personal information has changed, if you believe that we have incorrect personal information about you, or if you simply want to review your personal information for accuracy, you may contact our Customer Service Department by sending an email through the Contact Us page on the Site located at http://www.drmartens.com/Contact.asp or calling toll free at 1-800-810-6673 (United States) or 0044 (0)845 769 7178 __ (outside of the United States).

The length of time we keep your information will vary depending on the nature of your transactions, on the Site and personal information involved. We have retention standards that meet customer service, legal and regulatory needs. For these reasons, we may keep your information beyond the end of your relationship with us. When your information is no longer required, we will dispose of it with appropriate care and diligence. Details about information we retain, the period and purpose for which it is retained as well as details about our disposal process, can be obtained by contacting our Customer Service Department toll free at 1-800-810-6673 (United States) or 0044 (0)845 769 7178 __ (outside of the United States).

**  
Opt Out**

To modify your e-mail subscriptions, please let us know by following the instructions in any email newsletter or update that we send to you. Please note that due to email production schedules you may receive any emails already in production. To delete all of your online account information from our database, sign into the “My Account” section of our Site and remove your shipping address, billing address and payment information. This will effect a deletion of all of your information which we may hold, however, please note that we may retain information about your sales transactions in order to service those transactions and for record keeping, for such reasonable period of time as may be required in connection with any question concerning such transactions. You may opt out of receiving any advertising or marketing from us by contacting us through the Contact Us page on the Site located at http://www.drmartens.com/asp.

**  
Protecting Children’s Personal Information**

We do not collect or maintain information from children we know are under 13. Children under 13 may browse our online store but may not create an online account, order merchandise, create a wish list, subscribe to our newsletter or enter our online contests or sweepstakes. Other restrictions may apply in connection with your participation in a contest or sweepstakes sponsored by us.

**  
Security**

We have physical, electronic, and procedural security safeguards to protect and secure the information we collect. Nonetheless, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. Therefore, we cannot guarantee the security of any information you transmit to or from our Site, and you do so at your own risk.

**  
Application of Policy**

This Policy applies to all personal information collected through the Site or collected by other means and stored electronically by us in connection with the Site.
